Contact

jrepyak@att.net

www.linkedin.com/in/john-repyak (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Six Sigma

Root Cause Analysis

Advanced Product Quality Planning
(APQP)

Certifications

Certified Quality Auditor (CQA)
AS9100 Rev D, Internal Auditor
Certified Quality Engineer (CQE)
Six Sigma Black Belt (CSSBB)
Global Certified ISO 9001:2015 Lead
Auditor

Honors-Awards

Honda Supplier Support - Circle Assistance Network

Patents DRIVER INTERFACE UNIT

John Repyak, ASQ SSBB, CQE, CQA, IATF Auditor

Vice President of Quality, Operational Excellence, Strategic Planning, Continuous Improvement, Root Cause Analysis Greater Detroit Area

Summary

As a problem solver, John has never met a problem he couldn't solve.

Executive Management | Vice Presidents | Operational Excellence | Six Sigma | Program Management | Root Cause Analysis | Team Based Problem Solving | Shainin Red X Methods | Kepner Tregoe

John's passion is tackling the high risk, costly issues, and driving them back to root cause. He then highlights the quality system gaps, carefully crafts C-level strategic plans, and works with plant champions' input for global rollout.

John enthusiastically joined Hans Premium Water's top-notch executive team, whose philanthropic vision was to provide clean, pure water to the world. The company was to use revenues from systems sold, to fund units to the underdeveloped areas of the world with no access to clean, drinkable water.

Within 6 months, John spearheaded a continuous improvement initiative to solve 90% of the quality issues on their Gen 1 Water Purifying System.

Extensive team efforts were also underway on the Gen 2 model, preparing for a 2020 reveal. John boosted the executive team's launch efforts with the careful introduction of only the most applicable and powerful APQP tools and methods. Unfortunately, due to covid-19, funding for Gen 2 evaporated, thus the global initiative was put on hold.

Previously, John was Vice President of Quality Systems for Peterson Spring, a 100 year old, family owned automotive and commercial

parts supplier. With the C-level team engaged, he forged a strategic action planning process, chartered a World Class problem solving system, and designed a new product launch process.

During his tenure, John led the above initiatives to dramatically reduce the customer complaint rate from 3500 ppm to less than 1 ppm.

John has lived a rich and diverse career in the aerospace, medical device, automotive, and electronics industries, with powerhouse companies like Rockwell International, Hexcel, Denso, Eaton, and Dana.

He's trained over 10,000 people in Six Sigma methods.

HONDA OF AMERICA recognized John with a LIFETIME ACHIEVEMENT AWARD for repeatedly producing winning problem-solving teams, based on his custom and highly effective methods of Root Cause Analysis.

John lives in Michigan, with his wife and youngest daughter. They are the proud parents of 5 children. His hobbies include working on and driving high performance track vehicles, restoring vintage muscle cars, golfing, coffee roasting, gardening, camping, fishing, and kayaking. With his wife, he also creates elaborate costumes, masks, puppets, and props for their daughter's theater performances.

Experience

HANS™ Premium Water

Vice President of Quality / Head of Quality

November 2019 - Present (7 months)

Farmington Hills, Michigan, United States

Manufacturer of Premium Water Purification Systems.

Key Customers – Culligan Water, ECOWater Systems, HANS Premium Water Dealer Network.

\$2,850,000 projected savings by Reducing Field Claims by approximately 90%. Rescued several Key Customer Relationships by expedient investigation and resolution of issues. Created Key Metric Dashboards for Incoming Quality, In Process Quality and Customer Quality.

Conceived plans to harmonize multiple plant quality systems structures, ISO 9001 & ISO 13485. Constructed the Customer Quality database that tracks trends and improvements regarding customer complaints and warranty issues.

Uniquely applied the PFMEA methods to the Packaging, Delivery and Installation processes which led to total redesign of the packaging and elimination of all transportation related defect.

Peterson Spring
Vice President of Quality Systems
July 2015 - November 2019 (4 years 5 months)
Southfield Michigan

Manufacturer of Springs, Stampings & Wire Forms. Key Customers – GM, John Deere, Eaton, Cummins.

Chief Administrator for the company's Quality Management System across 10 plants. \$2,700,000 savings from reduced Customer Defects and external sorting costs.

Drove CPPM from 3500 in July of 2015 down to < 1 PPM by end of 2019. 86% reduction in the annual number of Customer Complaints. Reduced from 356 in 2015 down to 51.

Shrunk the Cost of Poor Quality from 2.78% of Sales down to 1.74%. Led the development & integration of IATF 16949 Quality Systems across 10 manufacturing plants

Led Supply Chain Optimization effort by consolidating the thousand of part numbers that shared common wire mills and material grades

Supported Engineering in DFSS, Design for Six Sigma, and DFX, Design for Excellence, activities during New Product Launch and Quoting Process.

Chassix Inc.

Senior Director of Quality & Continuous Improvement June 2010 - July 2015 (5 years 2 months)

Southfield, Michigan, United States

Manufacturer of Automotive Steering & Suspension Components.

Key Customers - Ford, Chrysler, GM, & Nissan.

Piloted a portfolio of cost reduction projects totaling over \$4,000,000 in annual savings. Reduced Customer Complaints from 3122 PPM in June of 2010 down to 36 PPM in 2014.

Saved over \$500,000 in personal scrap reduction projects with the first 3 Six Sigma Blitzes. Created a common Quality Metric system to drive improvements across 26 plants globally.

Reengineered the 5 Year Roll Out Strategy for the Continuous Improvement System. Mentored and trained Black Belts through the newly developed Six Sigma Blitz Initiative

Dana Corporation

Global Quality Systems Manager - ASQ CQE & SSBB November 2007 - May 2010 (2 years 7 months)

Kalamazoo, Michigan, United States

Manufacturer of Agricultural, Mining, and Construction Steer Axle Systems. Key Customers - John Deere, Case New Holland, Sandvik.

Decreased John Deere customer complaints by over 90% in 3 months using DOE and Six Sigma. Recouped key customer relationships, John Deere & Case New Holland, through face-to-face reviews.

Eliminated top causes for warranty: fractured sun gears, leaking face seals & transaxle shaft noise. Drove poka yokes for high-risk PFMEA RPN items such as bolt torques, oil leaks & missing parts

Eaton Truck Components

Quality Manager & Program Manager - Master Black Belt | Eaton Green Belt

August 2001 - November 2007 (6 years 4 months)

Galesburg, Michigan, United States

Manufacturer of Electronic Safety Systems and Automated Truck Transmissions.

Key Customers - Freightliner, Mack, Volvo, Navistar, Oshkosh Truck.

Was the Top Quality Plant Management Representative

Program Manager for Telematics Systems using vehicle radar and onboard CPU's to capture vehicle maintenance data, driver safety habits, and alert fleet safety managers to dangerous situations.

Managed a 100-vehicle field test to attain 99% reliability goals prior to end of new-product launch. Drove supplier corrective actions to reduce supplier PPM from 50,000 to below 1000. Reduced customer complaints from over 2500 PPM down below the 100 PPM level.

Led 6 Sigma efforts on AutoShift magnet adhesion warranty problem – estimated \$2,500,000 savings. Decreased #1 Warranty Issue - water intrusion for front-end radar – estimated \$200,000 savings. Eliminated a \$200,000 backlog of unsolved line fallout for VORAD products using 6 Sigma methods.

Led team in 3-year effort to be the first Eaton plant to win Freightliner's Masters of Quality Award. Championed & Trained local team members in the use of Six Sigma using CTQ's, PFMEA's, Minitab, Gage R&R's, capability studies, DOE's, SPC, correlation studies, and root cause analysis.

ASQ Certified Master Black Belt

Patent Application: DRIVER INTERFACE UNIT Publication number: 20090096597

Abstract: A system and method for detecting a plurality of vehicle conditions are disclosed. A system may include a plurality of inputs indicating a corresponding plurality of vehicle conditions, and a driver interface unit in communication with the inputs. The driver interface unit is operable to output one or more indicators associated with each vehicle condition, and to modify one of the indicators such that the driver interface unit outputs the modified indicator and the other indicators.

Inventors: Richard M. Avery, JR., David L. Flood, John P. Repyak, Alan W. Dudycha, Robert O. Anderson

Jabil

Operational Excellence Manager / Six Sigma and Lean Champion January 1999 - May 2001 (2 years 5 months)

Auburn Hills, Michigan, United States

Manufacturer of Automotive & Telecommunication circuit board assemblies. Key Customers - Lucent Technologies, Ascend, Cisco, JCI Johnson Controls.

Was the Top Quality Plant Management Representative for a 4 site campus.

Mistake proofed deviation database and workflow saving over \$1,000,000 in processing errors. Directed a quality department of 50+ managers, Black Belts, supervisors, and engineers.

Assisted Lean Manager during the introduction of Lean into the 4-building campus at Auburn Hills. Championed Lean project for Global Document Control and saved \$432,000 per year. Management Representative for QS 9000 and ISO 9001 quality management systems

JPR Consulting

President / Problem Solving Consultant August 1994 - May 1999 (4 years 10 months)

Portage, Michigan, United States

Consultant, Trainer and Continuous Improvement Team Coach.

Key Customers – Stryker Instruments, MACI Michigan Automotive Compressor

Inc., ARVCO Containers, Honda of America Supplier Network

Customized training programs for Stryker Instruments and ARVCO using S.U.R.E.F.I.R.E. Root Cause Analysis. Trained and mentored 5 teams of 5 people every several months over 3-year period. Mentoring sessions focused on each team's project and walked them through S.U.R.E.F.I.R.E. steps.

Focus Products included Sagittal Saw Motor Defects, Rotary Drill RPM issues, Disposable Blade Scrap, Impaction Rotor surface scratches, Heavy Duty Reamer and Micro Motor Coil Winding Scrap, etc..

Every team successfully solved their issues, many issues once deemed unsolvable.

DENSO

Advanced Quality Engineering & Quality Circle System Facilitator | Master Black Belt

August 1990 - January 1999 (8 years 6 months)

Battle Creek, Michigan, United States

Manufacturer of Automotive Air Conditioning and Heating Components.

Key Customers - Toyota, Honda, Mazda, Isuzu, CAMI, Chrysler, BMW, Mercedes.

Over \$10,000,000 saved in scrap, waste, customer defects and warranty costs company wide. Reduced condenser brazing, evaporator burst, and heater core leak scrap by over \$1,000,000 / year.

Reduced evaporator leak rate from 12% to 2% in just nine months. Created company wide Team Based problem solving program and recognition systems. Facilitated ~100 Green Belt and 20 Black Belt teams annually and led them to world-class excellence.

Trained over 10,000 associates and mentored over 1800 continuous improvement teams

Hexcel Corporation

Manufacturing Engineering & TQM Facilitator
September 1987 - August 1990 (3 years)

Graham, Texas, United States

Manufacturer of Aerospace Honeycomb Structural Products and Materials. Key Customers - Boeing, Northrup, General Dynamics, Bell Helicopter, Mcdonnell Douglas

Directed scrap task force committees and reduced overall scrap ratio by 66% in only 2 years. Resulted in over \$5,000,000 in reduced scrap and rework.

CNC Machining throughput improved 100%. Initiated and facilitated Total Quality Management (TQM) at the Graham, Texas facility. Taught DOE, and SPC to scrap reduction teams

ROCKWELL INTERNATIONAL

Project Coordinator / Industrial Engineer May 1984 - September 1987 (3 years 5 months)

Tulsa, Oklahoma, United States

Prime Contractor of the B-1 Bomber, and Space Shuttle

Developed and activated the production facilities for B-1 Bomber and Space Shuttle programs. Managed capital & expense budgets for projects in excess of \$2,000,000 every year

Endex & Shell Commercial Security & Surveilance Systems Team Leader / Electronics Technician March 1982 - May 1984 (2 years 3 months)

Led multiple teams of installers and technicians for large projects involving skyscrapers and maximum-security prisons.

Products include CCTV, Fire Alarm, gate Access, Microwave/Ultrasonic/Infrared security systems.

Education

Iowa State University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Industrial Engineering Technology · (1978 - 1981)

Illinois State University
Business/Commerce, General · (1977 - 1978)